<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Legislative Intent &amp; Ordinary Meaning</title>
    <link>https://merryxmasfromhegel.github.io/law-language/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Legislative Intent &amp; Ordinary Meaning</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>shaolong.chen@outlook.it (Shaolong Chen)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>shaolong.chen@outlook.it (Shaolong Chen)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© 2024 Shaolong Chen</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://merryxmasfromhegel.github.io/law-language/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Blad v Bamfield</title>
      <link>https://merryxmasfromhegel.github.io/law-language/second-test-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shaolong.chen@outlook.it (Shaolong Chen)</author>
      <guid>https://merryxmasfromhegel.github.io/law-language/second-test-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;legal-fictions&#34;&gt;Legal fictions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Perpetual injunction to restrain proceedings against a Dane, for tlie seizure of property of English subjects in Iceland, the seizure being sanctionsd by the Danish, authorities.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case of Peter Blad, a subject of Denmark, against Bamfield and Others, came now to be heard (of which see the beginning before at the council board (see the preceding case), and the scope of the suit was to stay several actions commenced at law in trespass and trover, for seizing certain  goods of the Defendants for trading in Iceland, contrary to certain privileges claimed there by the Plaintiff and others. The Defendants insisted that tins was no cause of state, and was ergo dismissed from the council table; that the injuries they had suffered were great, and such as were done with gome kind of affront to and contempt of the English nation ; that they had a most undoubted right of trade in Iceland, and by the articles of peace with Denmark, were to use their commerce with the subjects of Denmark without molestation ; that if the King of Denmark had granted any patents of privilege contrary to the freedom of trade, they were illegal, and a breach of the treaty in question ; and if the patents were of ancienter date, they had been dispensed with by the contrary practice, which had suffered English to trade there, and so invited the Defendants ; that, however, the Plaintiff had already had all the benefit of this Court which he could reasonably expect, for he obtained an injunction till he had examined his witnesses, and now having perfected his proofs, whatever could avail him here, would also avail him at law ; wherefore they prayed leave, that now, at last, they might go to their trial at law.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="legal-fictions">Legal fictions</h1>
<p><em>Perpetual injunction to restrain proceedings against a Dane, for tlie seizure of property of English subjects in Iceland, the seizure being sanctionsd by the Danish, authorities.</em></p>
<p>The case of Peter Blad, a subject of Denmark, against Bamfield and Others, came now to be heard (of which see the beginning before at the council board (see the preceding case), and the scope of the suit was to stay several actions commenced at law in trespass and trover, for seizing certain  goods of the Defendants for trading in Iceland, contrary to certain privileges claimed there by the Plaintiff and others. The Defendants insisted that tins was no cause of state, and was ergo dismissed from the council table; that the injuries they had suffered were great, and such as were done with gome kind of affront to and contempt of the English nation ; that they had a most undoubted right of trade in Iceland, and by the articles of peace with Denmark, were to use their commerce with the subjects of Denmark without molestation ; that if the King of Denmark had granted any patents of privilege contrary to the freedom of trade, they were illegal, and a breach of the treaty in question ; and if the patents were of ancienter date, they had been dispensed with by the contrary practice, which had suffered English to trade there, and so invited the Defendants ; that, however, the Plaintiff had already had all the benefit of this Court which he could reasonably expect, for he obtained an injunction till he had examined his witnesses, and now having perfected his proofs, whatever could avail him here, would also avail him at law ; wherefore they prayed leave, that now, at last, they might go to their trial at law.</p>
<p>I said never was any cause more properly before the Court than the case in question ; first, as it relates to a trespass done upon the high sea, which though it may seem to belong to the cognisance of the admiral, yet I took this occasion to show that the Court of Chancery hath always had an admiral jurisdiction, not only per viam appellationis, but per viam evocationis too, and may send for any cause out of the Admiralty to determine it here ; of which there are many precedents in Not/&rsquo;s MSS. 88 ; and in my little book, in the preface, de offlcio Cancellarii, sect. 18 ; and in my parchment book in octavo, tit. Admiralty (3 Strans. 604); secondly, as it had relation to articles of peace, all leagues and safe conducts being anciently enrolled in this court. That it is very true this cause was dismissed from the Council Board, being not looked on there as a case of state, because for ought appeared to them, it might be a private injury, and unwarrantable, and so fit to be left to a legal dis¡cussion ; but now, the very manner of the defence offered by the Defendants had made it directly a case of state ; for they insist upon the articles of peace to justify their commerce, which is of vast consequence to the public ; for every misinterpreta¡tion of an article may be the unhappy occasion of a war ; and if it had been known at Board that this would have been the main part of their case, doubtless the Council would not have suffered it to depend in Westminster Hall. But in truth this pretence of articles of peace must needs fail the Defendants; for the articles of free trade are reciprocal, and are understood on both sides, with exception to the laws and customs of each kingdom. Put the case then that a Danish ship should trade to the Bar-badoes, or any other of his majesty&rsquo;s foreign plantations, and were thereupon taken and seized, or should break in upon the privileges granted by his majesty to the East India Company, and were there arrested at Bantam or Fort St. George, doubtless this were no breach of the treaty on our part; and if any of his majesty&rsquo;s subjects who seized that ship at the Barbadoes, or judges, should be then molested and prose¡cuted in Denmark, in a private action, for what they did in obedience to the laws of their king and country, it would look like such a breach on their part as might well occasion a further rupture on ours. Ergo, to come now to the present ease, certainly no case was ever better proved ; for the Plaintiff hath proved letters patent from the King of Denmark for the sole trade of Iceland ; a seizure by virtue of that patent ; a sentence upon that seizure ; a confirmation of that sentence by the Chancellor of Denmark ; an execution of that sentence after confirmation ; and a payment of two thirds to the King of Denmark after that execution. Now, after all this, to send it to a trial at law, where either the Court must pretend to judge of the validity of the king&rsquo;s letters patent in Denmark, or of the exposition and meaning of the articles of peace ; or that a common jury should try whether the English have a right to trade in Iceland, is monstrous and absurd.</p>
<p>Wherefore the whole state of the case appearing now before me, as much as ever it can do in any other place, I thought fit to put an end to it, and decreed that the Plaintiff should have a perpetual injunction to stay the Defendant&rsquo;s suit at law ; and that satisfaction should be acknowledged upon that judgment which the Plaintiff had acknowledged to the Defendants as a temporary security till the hearing of the cause.</p>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Legal fictions</title>
      <link>https://merryxmasfromhegel.github.io/law-language/placeholder-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shaolong.chen@outlook.it (Shaolong Chen)</author>
      <guid>https://merryxmasfromhegel.github.io/law-language/placeholder-text/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;fiction-meaning-and-interpretation&#34;&gt;Fiction, meaning and interpretation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I said earlier that legal fictions allow us to modify the reach of the law in particular cases or kinds of case without reinterpreting legal terms. This is one valuable feature of legal fictions brought out by my account. In this section, I’ll elaborate on this point by contrasting legal fictions with an alternative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic problem addressed by legal fictions is this. There is a legal rule that attaches consequences to falling under a certain word, like ‘clergyman’ or ‘dependant.’ In some kinds of case, there are reasons why the consequences should apply even though the word’s requirements are not satisfied, or the consequences should not apply even though the word’s requirements are satisfied. Legal fictions allow us to arrive at the right result without revising the legal rule. Of course, wherever there is a reason to use a legal fiction, there is also a reason to revise the legal rule. So, the technique of legal fictions is particularly useful where there are constraints on our ability to revise the legal rule.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="fiction-meaning-and-interpretation">Fiction, meaning and interpretation</h1>
<p>I said earlier that legal fictions allow us to modify the reach of the law in particular cases or kinds of case without reinterpreting legal terms. This is one valuable feature of legal fictions brought out by my account. In this section, I’ll elaborate on this point by contrasting legal fictions with an alternative.</p>
<p>The basic problem addressed by legal fictions is this. There is a legal rule that attaches consequences to falling under a certain word, like ‘clergyman’ or ‘dependant.’ In some kinds of case, there are reasons why the consequences should apply even though the word’s requirements are not satisfied, or the consequences should not apply even though the word’s requirements are satisfied. Legal fictions allow us to arrive at the right result without revising the legal rule. Of course, wherever there is a reason to use a legal fiction, there is also a reason to revise the legal rule. So, the technique of legal fictions is particularly useful where there are constraints on our ability to revise the legal rule.</p>
<p>However, it might seem that there is another, simpler way to get to the right results without revising the legal rule. To see this, consider what Ronald Dworkin might say about the death benefits case. For Dworkin, legal interpretation is assessed on the axes of fit and justification: the best interpretation of the law will be the one that best fits with the legal materials and justifies them, or shows them in their best light (Dworkin, 1986, p. 230). Legal interpretation is subject to distinct normative pressures, pressures that can pull the legal meaning of a term apart from its ordinary meaning. Given the moral value of providing for children, it might be argued that, on its best interpretation, the word ‘dependant’ has to include subsequently born children. If this is right, then there is no need for a legal fiction: a court can engage in an interpretive exercise and determine that the child D counts as a dependant.</p>
<p>Someone who takes this interpretive approach doesn’t have to say that ‘dependant’ always includes subsequently born children. Rather, they can argue that the meaning of many terms varies between ordinary and legal contexts, given the distinct normative pressures that apply in legal contexts. Meanings may even vary between different legal contexts. In an ordinary context, ‘dependant’ does not include subsequently born children; in some legal contexts, it does, such that there is no need for a legal fiction to get to the right result. This may be seen as an instance of the more general phenomenon of meaning varying with context. For example, the meaning of ‘today’ varies with the day when the word is used, and the meaning of ‘loud’ might be different in a library and a concert venue.</p>
<p>To be clear, this alternative proposal involves a less predictable kind of meaning-variation than cases like ‘today’ and ‘loud.’ In those cases, the rule governing the use of the word stays the same between contexts, while the semantic contribution of the word varies in a constrained way (Kaplan, 1989). This is why you can learn it in one context and be able to use it in another. The way legal meaning comes apart from ordinary meaning need not be this constrained: knowing what ‘dependant’ means in ordinary contexts need not allow you to determine what it means in legal contexts. Still, I agree that there are words whose meanings vary between ordinary and legal contexts. For example, ‘consideration’ means different things in ordinary and legal contexts; knowing what it ordinarily means does not allow you to determine what it means in law. So too for ‘person.’</p>
<p>But while this kind of variation is a real phenomenon in legal language, I don’t think it offers a complete alternative to legal fictions (Fuller, 1930–1931a, p. 379). The two techniques — meaning-variation and fictions — suit different problems. Meaning-variation is most apt where there are reasons — general to the legal order, or at least a large part of it — why the legal meaning of a word should diverge from its ordinary meaning. The legal meanings of ‘consideration’ and ‘person’ play a role across the legal order. By contrast, fictions are most apt where there are reasons local to one kind of legal situation to (mis)apply a term. The fictional application of ‘dependant’ to subsequently born children is specific to death benefits cases.</p>
<p>The difference between these two techniques matters because multiplying meanings comes with a cost. Whenever the legal meaning of a term diverges in an unpredictable way from its ordinary meaning, participants in the legal order have to learn a new meaning in order to understand and engage with that legal rule. This cost is more likely to be worth it where the legal meaning plays a role across the legal order. If the legal meaning is specific to one kind of case — for example, if participants will have to track the difference between what ‘dependant’ means in most legal cases and what it means in death benefits cases — then fictions offer a more epistemically accessible way to get to the right result (Levenbook, 2022).  Instead of learning a new meaning, participants only have to exercise their capacity for make-believe. This is a capacity that we have independent reason to attribute to subjects like us.
Indeed, I would suggest that, even by Dworkin’s own standards, an interpretation of the law that includes legal fictions might be superior to one that assigns variant meanings to legal terms wherever necessary to get to the right results. Of course, if all we had to work with was the word ‘dependant,’ then an interpretation of ‘dependant’ that included subsequently born children would be better than one that did not. But that is not all we have to work with. We don’t interpret terms one at a time; rather, we interpret the law as a whole. So, we should be comparing two interpretations of the law as a whole: one that interprets ‘dependant’ to include subsequently born children, and another that does not, but in which courts can fictionally apply ‘dependant’ to those children in the death benefits context. The fiction-involving interpretation certainly fares better on the axis of fit. As to justification, both interpretations provide benefits to the children who need them, but the fiction-involving interpretation may also be more epistemically accessible.</p>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
